Finding Aid for Gay Delanghe papers, 1961-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Programs and Publicity, 1961-2005
  - "Duets,", October 24, 1976 (Box 5)
  - "La Création du Monde,", December 10-12, 1976 (Box 5)
  - "Primordial Figures,", March 18-20, 1977 (Box 5)
  - "Satiana,", July 22-23, 1977 (Box 5)
  - "Preclassics,", October 16, 1977 (Box 5)
  - "Primordial Figures,", November 18-20, 1977 (Box 5)
  - "Cuchulain Saga,", March 15-19, 1978 (Box 5)
  - "Pre-classic," "two Dances in Memory of Edgar Varese,", March 24-25, 1978 (Box 5)
  - "Kammersinfonien,", April 7-8, 1978 (Box 5)
  - "French Suite II," "Primordial Figures," "Two Dances in Memory of Edgar Varese,", August 17-20, 1978 (Box 5)
  - "A Full Moon in March,", March 1979 (Box 5)
  - "A Full Moon in March,", April 17-21, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "Two Dances in Memory of Edgar Varese,", May 13, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "Three Easy Pieces," "Shawl Dance," "Two Dances in Memory of Edgar Varese," French Suite,", May 31-June 2, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "Vintage Rags,", June 16-17, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Interlochen, July-August, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "Delanghe's Theme With Variations" (Video), October 13-14, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "Motor Tango,", October 18-20, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "Seven Deadly Sins,", November 16-17, 1979 (Box 5)
  - "A Ceremony of Carols,", December 7-9, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Visiting Lecture, "Le Group Nouvelle Aire,", February 29-March 1, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Seven Deadly Sins," "Carmina Burana,", March 13-16, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Allemande, Courante and Gigue," "Two Dances and Memory of Edgar Varese," "Motor Tango,", April 7, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Delanghe's Theme" (Video), May 30, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Interlochen, July-August, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Motor Tango,", September 5-6, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Allemande, Courante and Gigue," "Greed," "Two Dances in Memory of Edgar Varese," "Motor Tango,", October 1, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Histoire du Soldat,", November 2, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Toccata and Big Fugue," "Little Fugue,", November 14-16, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Album,", December 5-6, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Winter Dance Extravaganza,", December, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Two Dances in Memory of Edgar Varese," "Motor Tango,", December 21, 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Rag-Time,", January 23, 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Seven Deadly Sins," "Motor Tango,", March 13-14, 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Solo Piano, Solo Dance,", June 24-25, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Interlochen, July 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Toccata Dirge,", September 11-12, 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Wind Song," "Black Figure," "Slap Happening," "Toccata Dirge,", November 13-15, 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Seven Deadly Sins,", December 9-12, 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Motor Tango,", December 11-13, 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Black Figure,", January 23, 1982 (Box 5)
  - "Black Figure," "Slap Happening,", April 2-3, 1982 (Box 5)
  - "Black Figure," "Toccata Dirge," "A Curtain of White," "slap Happening,", May 13-15, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Interlochen, July-August 1982 (Box 5)
  - Wayne State Arts Achievement Award, October 9, 1982 (Box 5)
  - "Doris Chase Dance Series" (Video), MCA Grant Recipients Exhibition, October 16-November 13, 1982 (Box 5)
  - "1-6 Plus 2 Other Indulgences,", March 4-5, 1983 (Box 5)
  - "1-6 Plus 6 More and Two Other Indulgences,", May 20, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Interlochen, July-August 1983 (Box 5)
  - "Detroit-er-ella,", September 9-10, 1983 (Box 5)
  - "Trois Danses,", October 17, 1983 (Box 5)
  - "Five Teas,", December 2-3, 1983 (Box 5)
  - "Motor Tango,", February 3-4, 1984 (Box 5)
  - "Trois Danses,", February 18, 1984 (Box 5)
  - "Nocturnes," "Two Sassy Brassies,", November 2-4, 1984 (Box 5)
  - "Dancin' Fats,", November 1, 1985 (Box 5)
  - "Living in Wilds," "Small Monsters,", December 5-7, 1985 (Box 5)
  - "Night and Day," "Small Monsters,", November 13-15, 1987 (Box 5)
  - "Dancin' Fats,", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "To the Market,", November 30-December 3, 1989 (Box 5)
  - "Humandinos: The End of the World as We Know It,", February 8-11, 1990 (Box 5)
  - "Icarus," "Lizzy's Revenge,", September 15, 1990 (Box 5)
  - "Icarus,", February 7-10, 1991 (Box 5)
  - "Picasso Projects,", Spring 1992 (Box 5)
  - "Icarus,", May 30-31, 1992 (Box 5)
  - "Rags," "Satiana,", May 20-22, 1993 (Box 5)
  - "Satiana," September 18-19, 1993 (Box 5)
  - "Murders," Interlochen, July 26-27, 1994 (Box 5)
  - "Sempre Con Grand Passione,", March 15, 1995 (Box 5)
  - "Blue Skies with Occasional Thunder from the Chairman," Interlochen, August 18-19, 1995 (Box 5)
  - "Harpies,", April 26-27, 1997 (Box 5)
  - "Italian Concerto in F Major., BWV 971,", June 15-16, 2000 (Box 5)
  - "Venice, Milan, Florenza,", September 27-28, 2000 (Box 5)
  - "Emotion Ocean,", June 14-15, 2001 (Box 5)
  - "Together,", December 1, 2001 (Box 5)
  - "Oceans of Motion and Emotion,", February 27, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "QE1,", March 16-17, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "QE1,", May 3, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "Statues in Motion," "QE1,", June 13-14, 2002 (Box 5)
- Teaching
  Records relating to Delanghe's activities as a professor of dance appear in the Teaching series. These records contain lecture notes, syllabi, and various teaching materials developed by Delanghe for graduate, undergraduate and mini-courses. Most of this material is undated. This series supports an understanding of the breadth of Delanghe's teaching engagements at the University of Michigan, and also convey a sense of her particular pedagogical style and relationship with students.
  - "Statues in Motion,", October 4-5, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "Classical Statues in Motion,", November 16, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "Emotion Ocean,", December 2, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "36-16-8-8 and Elevator,", January 30-February 2, 2003 (Box 5)
  - "Venice, Florence, Milan," "The Dangerous Kitchen,", June 12-13, 2003 (Box 5)
  - "La Duncan and Fokine,", February 5-8, 2004 (Box 5)
  - "Statuary: Classics in Motion,", June 10-11, 2004 (Box 5)
  - "Excerpts from Minimal Moments,", July 24, 2004 (Box 5)
  - "Dancin' Fats,", February 3-6, 2005 (Box 5)
  - "La Duncan and Fokine," "Icarus,", March 18-20, 2005 (Box 5)
  - "Freeze Frame,", June 9-11, 2005 (Box 5)
  - "Freeze Frame," Dancin' Fats,", September 24, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Ballet 231 (Box 5)
  - Body Knowledge (Box 5)
  - Composition
    - Teaching Materials (Box 5)
    - Syllabi and Programs (Box 5)
  - Cultural Concepts (Box 5)
  - Dance and Related Arts (Box 5)
  - Dance Production (Box 5)
  - Education (304, 307) (Box 5)
  - Field Experience (Box 5)
  - Graduate Choreography (CP and D) (Box 5)
  - ImMERCEsion (Box 5)
  - Labanotation (Box 6)
  - Lifeforms (Box 6)
  - Methods of Dance (350) (Box 6)
  - Modern Dance (Box 6)
  - Special Topics (490) (Box 6)
  - Viewing Professional Dance (Box 6)
- University of Michigan Department of Dance, 1995-2001
  The University of Michigan Department of Dance series contains materials directly relating to Delanghe's administrative duties while she served as department chair (1995-2001). These records include student lists, some departmental correspondence, and information on the School of Education's accreditation of the department's teaching certification program. The series also contains some general records relating to the activities of Ann Arbor Dance Works, the resident dance company for the department's faculty members, which Delanghe co-founded with her colleagues, Peter Sparling, Jessica Fogel, Bill DeYoung, and Linda Spriggs, in 1984.
  - Ann Arbor Dance Works (Box 6)
  - Faculty Reports, 1997-2004 (Box 6)
  - Grading Policies (Box 6)
  - School of Education Accreditation (Box 6)
  - Students and Alumni Lists (Box 6)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1972-2006
  Audiovisual Materials (1972-2006) contains a variety of video and film formats documenting dance performances, and rehearsals from various points in Delanghe's career. The tapes are mostly labeled, though their contents have not been verified to correspond to their given titles. Slides contains a variety of labeled and unlabeled slides used in lectures and presentations, as well as in performances.
  - VHS and Beta Sp,Undated
    - "Spacial Etchings/Smith/Motet/Verlezza/Rampage/French Suite Delanghe,", 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Alma Icarus" (spine) "Icarus UM Dc. Co." (tape), 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Delanghe/AADW Bach Trio" (spine) "Italian AADW" (tape), 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Harpies Popart,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Slap Happening,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Lucas Satie/Limon Dub,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Delanghe Dino Sketches,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Interlochen Dancers?,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Fats For Five Dancers Plus One/Fats For Fifteen But One Dancer Missing,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "All of a Feather," "U of Mich., AA Dance Works,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Reel to Reel Dub,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Webern,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Motor Tango," "Seven Deadly Sins,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Goreski Work,", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
  - VHS and Beta Sp, Dated
    - "Aubade 72," "Satiana 78," "FATS IAC 91,", 1972-1991; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "Creation 76," "Tears 75?,", 1975-1976; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "SINS,", 1980; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
    - "SINS,", March 12, 1980; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 7)
      VHS Copy of master 3/4 tape (A)
    - "NMC Rinaldo, Goler, Rosenfeld, Delanghe #1,", 1980; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 7)
    - "NMC #2,", 1980; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "NMC Delanghe, Rinaldo, Barreau, Johnson, Van Kuiken, Barreau,", 1981; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Hoving, Power,", 1981; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Gay Delanghe Motor Tango, Liz Bergman Tikal,", December 1981; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Blk Fig, Toccata, Slap, Gp Work Schoenbeg, French 2 Varese/Primordial, Creation,", 1982; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "NMC O'Rourke, Van Kuiken, Delanghe,", Summer 1982; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "NMC VanKuiken, Krzyminksi, Lommasson,", 1983; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "NMC Vegas on the Lake, Without the Rain, Ceremonial,", 1984; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Fats Rags Chopin Dub Monsters Wilds Vivaldi,", 1984; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "NMC Comp Show,", 1986; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Limon Co. "There is a Time," Limon Technique by D. Lewis,", 1986; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Worktape--Boogie, Red/Black and White," "Knock" Fall, Fall 1986; 1987; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "NMC Modern Works 1. HVK, 2. BDY, 3. MF,", 1986; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "1. Down River, 2. Night and Day: Henry and Gay,", November 14, 1987; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Old Rags 88," "Icarus 89 (80),", 1988-1989; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "All of a Feather, Ann Arbor Dance Works #1 and #2,", January 18, 1988; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Satie, Market 1989 AADW 1993 Gay Steve Linda," 1989, 1993, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works 5th Anniversary", December 2, 1989; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Interlochen--Corson Faculty Concert,", July 26, 1990; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Dino Dance Gay! Dada-da,", February 20, 1990; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Gay Delanghe September Dances,", 1990; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Dancin' Fats" "Shenandoah Dance Ensemble,", May, 1990; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 8)
    - "Pride and Prejudice (1+2)--Power Center,", Fall 1990; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Interlochen--Corson--Rehearsal,", July 23, 1990; 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Joplin/Stravinsky/Albright "Not On Here",", 1990; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Pride and Prejudice Original,", 1990; 1991; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Lizzy's Revenge, A2DCWKS,", Fall 1991; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Without Amy in Connoisseurs of Chaos" "Ann Arbor Dance Works Studio A, S, May 20, 1993; 2 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
      Master and copy
    - "Murders Dress Perform, IAC,", 1994; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Play Re-Play, IAA,", August 20, 1994; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Migrations, Part II: AADW,", April, 1996; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "2. Gorecki, 1. Muybridge Dub 05, 3. Harpies,", 1996; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Tanzmusik" "Serioso Now and Then (Fogel), 2. Waltzscape (Delanghe), 3. Esplanade (Taylor),", February 1997; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works 14th Spring Anniversary Concert,", April 24-25, 1998; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Doris Chase Circle at the Center, KCT-TV Seattle Washington,", 1999; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "EEPC Home Season Excerpts," 1999., 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "University of Michigan School of Dance Ann Arbor Dance Works", June 14-15, 2001; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "AADW 02 Queens-Statues,", 2002; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Delanghe--Interludes,", December, 2002; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works and Detroit Dance Collective In a Shared Concert,", June 13, 2002; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 9)
    - "University of Michigan School of Dance, Resonant Rhythms," January 31, 2003, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 10)
    - "University of Michigan School of Music, University Dance Company "Dances for Petersburg",", February 5 2004; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 10)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works 20th Spring Season,", June 11, 2004; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 10)
  - U-Matic/Open Reel
    - "Icarus,", 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Chase/Delanghe,", August 14, 1979; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "NMC Faculty Concert Worktape: Little Fugue, Toccata, Big Fugue, VanKuiken, MacDonald, Goler, Delanghe, Rinaldo,", 1980; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Solomons Delanghe Matheke Power,", Fall 1980; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Power Center Spring Concert 3. Winter Ebb, 4. A Day in the Life of...,", 1981; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "David Snyder Part 2, NMC Faculty Concert,", 1983; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Five Teas, Power Center, Gay Delanghe, UM Dance Company,", 1983; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Dancing Fats Choreographer: Gay Delanghe, "Contemporary Dance Theater,", 1984; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Smooth as Glass," For Luci--,", Winter 1984; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 10)
    - "Pre-Classics--Recorded in Studio #A,", 1978; 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 10)
    - "Bach Outside,", 1978; 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 10)
    - "Girlie-Delanghe, Variations-Bergman, Afro,", 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 10)
    - "1. Tap-Gary, Tears-Gay Delanghe,", 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 11)
    - "2. Tap-Gary, Tears-Gay Delanghe,", 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 11)
    - "#4 1. Ballet, 2. Elegy, 3. Delanghe (Lesch) (Power 1972) 24,", 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 11)
    - "Delanghe Monsters", Winter 1988; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "Dance Works Tape #2 Gay Delanghe All of a Feather,", November, 1988; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "NMC: Delanghe, VanKuiken,", 1988; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "Gay Delanghe A2 Dance Works Going to the Market,", April 1989; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "Gay Delanghe Rags/Power,", February 3, 1989 (Box 11)
    - "Minstrel Tunes," "White Flag-Blackface-Ragtime,", February 4, 1989; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "Pride and Prejudice,", Fall 1990; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "Icarus,", February 10, 1991 (Box 11)
    - "Dances by Linda Spriggs, Gay Delanghe Performance," S, May 20, 1993; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 11)
    - "Dances by Linda Spriggs, Gay Delanghe Rehearsal," S, May 19, 1993; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 11)
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works: Madonna", 1988; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 11)
    - "Satiana: Limon Co. Manhattanville,", July, 1977; 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 11)
    - "#4 Bullshot, Slavonic Skaena, Aubade,", 1 video recordings open reel videotapes (Box 11)
  - Super 8 film
    - "Aubade,", Summer 1973; 3 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "N. Topf Circle,", Summer 1973; 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Limb NY,", June, 1973; 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Limb Central Park,", June, 1974; 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - Untitled, 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Perez,", Summer 1973; 4 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Seven Deadly Sins", 6 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Bassett", 3 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Don Davidson, Good Roll", 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Don Davidson, Bad Roll", 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "H. Delanghe 2975 Beals, Detroit 14, Michigan", 2 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
    - "Waterman Bob and Carol,", May 1973; 1 film reels Super 8 (Box 12)
  - Hi 8 Video
    - "Ann Arbor Dance Works,", 2003; 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
    - "Women Who Rule: Fogel, Setrackian, Sears-Etter, Delanghe,", March 17, 2002; 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
    - "IAC #1 Perform (No Bonus),", 1996; 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
    - "IAC Nite,", 1996; 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
    - "362", 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
    - "#1 Rough Harpies Work, Migrations,", 1996; 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
    - "Dance Works Tape #1, Good Harpies No Migrations,", April, 1996; 1 film reels Hi8 (Box 12)
  - DVD
    - "Hommage a Delanghe Final Short,", May 20, 2006; 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 12)
    - "Icarus Backup", 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 12)
    - "Gay's Slideshow", 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 12)
    - "Hommage á Delanghe (short version)", 1 optical disks DVDs
  - Slides
    - Tom Mills, Cliff, From Interlochen Dances, 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - Barnard Dance Classes, Spring 1971 (Box 13)
    - Barnard Adv Class and MWz Low, Spring 1971 (Box 13)
    - Barnard Dance Classes Lo-Int, Spring 1971 (Box 13)
    - Jim Hunter Sins Power, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Me At Cat House, February 1978 (Box 13)
    - Limon Workshop, 2 cases (Box 13)
    - Bela P.E. Dance Conference Eastern Michigan University, November 1975 (Box 13)
    - Uppercase, Fall 1974 (Box 13)
    - Composition, Fall 1989 (Box 13)
    - Comp 261, Fall 1990 (Box 13)
    - Chris, Summer 1975 (Box 13)
    - SWS Rehearsal, Fall 1975 (Box 13)
    - Some Uppercase Classes, Jazz Sylvie, Ballet Gay, Fall 1974 (Box 13)
    - Power, April 1975 (Box 13)
    - Play Girl Slides (Box 13)
    - Sins Rehearsal, Fall 1975 (Box 13)
    - Schoenberg (Box 13)
    - Unlabeled, 3 boxes, 1 carousel, 5 sleeves (Box 13)
Related Material
Additional material on Gay Dealnghe and other dance collections at the Bentley Historical Library can be found at http://bentley.umich.edu/exhibits/dance